<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>essays on Making Principles</title>
    <link>/tags/essays/</link>
    <description>Recent content in essays on Making Principles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Ari Akerstein 2006</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/essays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Things we assume</title>
      <link>/posts/assumptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/assumptions/</guid>
      <description>Emotions are challenging. As a child I turned them off - at least showing them to the world - they were an achilles heel, a source of weakness in a world that felt hostile.&#xA;But as humans imagine a generation that has lost the ability to feel. It might take many generations to relearn those abilities. This is the culture. We learn the abilities. But do we learn how to feel?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Field of Play</title>
      <link>/posts/fieldofplay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/fieldofplay/</guid>
      <description>What is a field of play? Before engaging in play, it&amp;rsquo;s good to obsess over the board. What do I mean? It&amp;rsquo;s been my experience that certain tactile or visceral components will set my mind racing about possibilities. And these possibilities would fire both before and after any daily engagement. The field fuels obsession.&#xA;Examples from my experience: In high school I played lacrosse. We would get use of Brown universities astroturf roof (&amp;ldquo;the roof&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Loops</title>
      <link>/posts/open-loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/open-loops/</guid>
      <description>I pass over a graveyard. If I had to guess I would say the overwhelming majority of bones beneath the stones had unfinished business - open loops.&#xA;Yom Kippur is the Jewish response to solving this issue and putting it on the calendar.&#xA;March is about closing open loops of projects. Here’s one – the radio that’s sitting in my basement. We got 90% of the way done then put it aside and that was that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aperture</title>
      <link>/posts/aperture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/aperture/</guid>
      <description>Nature opens her aperture through the consciousness of humans. We are nature, instantiated. The peril is not realizing the window of opportunity that exists for those of us blessed to live outside the survival envelope (in which we spend most of our time on survival-related activities). It’s worth stepping back and considering the absence of hardships we might easily have suffered.&#xA;The young have much to learn from the older members of humanity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Factory Floor</title>
      <link>/posts/factory-floor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/factory-floor/</guid>
      <description>The cursor pulses hot green against the black terminal. A few quick taps execute the script. I watch the simulation unfold on the screen. Then, a stocatto barrage of keystrokes: Simulation number 39…no change from 38…The pX protein displays kinetics suggesting diffusion as the primary mechanic of nucleus traversal. In the presence of DNA breaks the molecular kinetics change and the molecule activates a cascade catalyzing repair complex formation…&#xA;I stop and lean back in the creaky lab chair.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye Grandma</title>
      <link>/posts/goodbye-grandma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/goodbye-grandma/</guid>
      <description>On the way to seeing her I jotted down the memories, talking point bullets in my notebook: the warm feeling from sitting on the carpet as a kid, the smell of spaghetti and meatballs permeating the air on a random weeknight; coming over for breakfast across the driveway for Kasha; etc. I wanted to sit with her and share those memories, I knew by this point she wasn’t likely to be lucid but still, maybe she could hear/recognize my voice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2009 Boston Marathon Race Report</title>
      <link>/posts/goboston-marathon-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/goboston-marathon-2009/</guid>
      <description>The day begins at 4:30. I must have eaten more than I can remember the previous night. I cooked up a vat of pasta, garlic bread and salad for a few folks including some fellow K-star runners. We watch chariots of fire on the 40” screen while shoveling the food down.&#xA;Out the door I get some green tea and honey at the local Starbucks (a staple for my marathons). On the bus ride over the course I feel disconcertingly unexcited.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
