<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>logs on Making Principles</title>
    <link>/categories/logs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in logs on Making Principles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Ari Akerstein 2006</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/logs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Making my Bed</title>
      <link>/posts/build-a-bed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/build-a-bed/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve heard people say it&amp;rsquo;s good to make your bed. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d take this advice literally. So, I made my bed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finish Your Work</title>
      <link>/posts/finishyourwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/finishyourwork/</guid>
      <description>I recently read &amp;ldquo;Scrum&amp;rdquo; and several points hit home. In reflecting on my own intellectual and creative pursuits. While I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing product for well over a decade now there are definitely areas of continued improvement that are needed.&#xA;It Causes Frustration It’s like Zeno’s paradox; with each touch there’s a further distance from the finish line. Why? Because the habit of non-finishing accrues. So there’s a lack of urgency that begets further non-finishing patterns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sublime Moments</title>
      <link>/posts/logic-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/logic-magic/</guid>
      <description>Today I reviewed my year. I stared at the sheet of paper - a ledger weighing the good and the bad. As I stared at the page, a question: how many sublime moments did I have? So I added a third column, straight down the the middle of the sheet.&#xA;Sublime moments My first observation was there were not as many as I&amp;rsquo;d have thought. Second, these were enabled by removing the steady state background hum of agitations: distraction, judgment and worry, processing all the things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When to show your work</title>
      <link>/posts/when-to-show-your-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/when-to-show-your-work/</guid>
      <description>Holding onto work too long leads to stagnation, like part of a river branch flowing into a dead end swamp.&#xA;A good outcome for showing work is either some fundamental flaw is exposed or tweaks suggested to optimize it. Either way time (the only non-renewable resource) is preserved. Through a quick personal survey I&amp;rsquo;ve observed that my outcomes tend to be good the majority of the time when I show my work quickly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Less</title>
      <link>/posts/do-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/do-less/</guid>
      <description>We flew back from Boston a few days ago. I’ve encountered my share of turbulence on planes but this was the worst I had ever experienced. The metallic rattling of luggage in the overheads was sickening. I imagined getting torn to bits at 30k feet. I looked down at Lev, my boy, in the next seat. I noticed his thick wavy hair, freckled cheeks – pure boyishness! He was calmly staring at the seat ahead.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
