<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Product Craft on Making Principles</title>
    <link>/categories/product-craft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Product Craft on Making Principles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Ari Akerstein 2006</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/product-craft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Field of Play</title>
      <link>/posts/fieldofplay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/fieldofplay/</guid>
      <description>What is a field of play? Before engaging in play, it&amp;rsquo;s good to obsess over the board. What do I mean? It&amp;rsquo;s been my experience that certain tactile or visceral components will set my mind racing about possibilities. And these possibilities would fire both before and after any daily engagement. The field fuels obsession.&#xA;Examples from my experience: In high school I played lacrosse. We would get use of Brown universities astroturf roof (&amp;ldquo;the roof&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sputtering flame</title>
      <link>/posts/sputteringflame/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/sputteringflame/</guid>
      <description>What might a life of full immersion look like? I sometimes think that bliss would be found in single-minded obsession. With so much busyness it’s critical to protect one’s time. I’ve spent too many years flitting and bouncing my attention (intention attendance!) at multiple levels. It’s like a sputtering flame : moment by moment - slack vs. SMS vs. email pings vs. fly-by my desk conversations. Day to day - reacting vs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enable Us To Pull</title>
      <link>/posts/enable-us-to-pull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/enable-us-to-pull/</guid>
      <description>This is what a product manager (any great leader) must do. This is a deceptively simple phrase but there a lot packed in it. This describes the what and the how and the why for achieving success as a team leader.&#xA;Enable Enablement happens on multiple levels. Unblock sticking points. On any project there will be many sticking points including: (1) From above (e.g., leadership misalignments), (2) from within (e.g., intra-team process, dynamics, lack of cohesion etc.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
