<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Making Principles</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Making Principles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Ari Akerstein 2006</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Things we assume</title>
      <link>/posts/assumptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/assumptions/</guid>
      <description>Emotions are challenging. As a child I turned them off - at least showing them to the world - they were an achilles heel, a source of weakness in a world that felt hostile.&#xA;But as humans imagine a generation that has lost the ability to feel. It might take many generations to relearn those abilities. This is the culture. We learn the abilities. But do we learn how to feel?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Field of Play</title>
      <link>/posts/fieldofplay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/fieldofplay/</guid>
      <description>What is a field of play? Before engaging in play, it&amp;rsquo;s good to obsess over the board. What do I mean? It&amp;rsquo;s been my experience that certain tactile or visceral components will set my mind racing about possibilities. And these possibilities would fire both before and after any daily engagement. The field fuels obsession.&#xA;Examples from my experience: In high school I played lacrosse. We would get use of Brown universities astroturf roof (&amp;ldquo;the roof&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making my Bed</title>
      <link>/posts/build-a-bed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/build-a-bed/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve heard people say it&amp;rsquo;s good to make your bed. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d take this advice literally. So, I made my bed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finish Your Work</title>
      <link>/posts/finishyourwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/finishyourwork/</guid>
      <description>I recently read &amp;ldquo;Scrum&amp;rdquo; and several points hit home. In reflecting on my own intellectual and creative pursuits. While I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing product for well over a decade now there are definitely areas of continued improvement that are needed.&#xA;It Causes Frustration It’s like Zeno’s paradox; with each touch there’s a further distance from the finish line. Why? Because the habit of non-finishing accrues. So there’s a lack of urgency that begets further non-finishing patterns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sputtering flame</title>
      <link>/posts/sputteringflame/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/sputteringflame/</guid>
      <description>What might a life of full immersion look like? I sometimes think that bliss would be found in single-minded obsession. With so much busyness it’s critical to protect one’s time. I’ve spent too many years flitting and bouncing my attention (intention attendance!) at multiple levels. It’s like a sputtering flame : moment by moment - slack vs. SMS vs. email pings vs. fly-by my desk conversations. Day to day - reacting vs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plants, in general</title>
      <link>/posts/plants-in-general/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/plants-in-general/</guid>
      <description>The frisbee veers into the brush. Lua and I walk over. As we crouch over the planter box I look down and notice green protruding jaws cup two tablespoons of water. As I inch closer, I notice white spots, patterns and tiny teeth along the edges of the leaves.&#xA;I’m somewhat horrified, not by the threat of frozen violence, but rather by my lack of awareness about plants. I love nature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sublime Moments</title>
      <link>/posts/logic-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/logic-magic/</guid>
      <description>Today I reviewed my year. I stared at the sheet of paper - a ledger weighing the good and the bad. As I stared at the page, a question: how many sublime moments did I have? So I added a third column, straight down the the middle of the sheet.&#xA;Sublime moments My first observation was there were not as many as I&amp;rsquo;d have thought. Second, these were enabled by removing the steady state background hum of agitations: distraction, judgment and worry, processing all the things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When to show your work</title>
      <link>/posts/when-to-show-your-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/when-to-show-your-work/</guid>
      <description>Holding onto work too long leads to stagnation, like part of a river branch flowing into a dead end swamp.&#xA;A good outcome for showing work is either some fundamental flaw is exposed or tweaks suggested to optimize it. Either way time (the only non-renewable resource) is preserved. Through a quick personal survey I&amp;rsquo;ve observed that my outcomes tend to be good the majority of the time when I show my work quickly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Loops</title>
      <link>/posts/open-loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/open-loops/</guid>
      <description>I pass over a graveyard. If I had to guess I would say the overwhelming majority of bones beneath the stones had unfinished business - open loops.&#xA;Yom Kippur is the Jewish response to solving this issue and putting it on the calendar.&#xA;March is about closing open loops of projects. Here’s one – the radio that’s sitting in my basement. We got 90% of the way done then put it aside and that was that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aperture</title>
      <link>/posts/aperture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/aperture/</guid>
      <description>Nature opens her aperture through the consciousness of humans. We are nature, instantiated. The peril is not realizing the window of opportunity that exists for those of us blessed to live outside the survival envelope (in which we spend most of our time on survival-related activities). It’s worth stepping back and considering the absence of hardships we might easily have suffered.&#xA;The young have much to learn from the older members of humanity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enable Us To Pull</title>
      <link>/posts/enable-us-to-pull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/enable-us-to-pull/</guid>
      <description>This is what a product manager (any great leader) must do. This is a deceptively simple phrase but there a lot packed in it. This describes the what and the how and the why for achieving success as a team leader.&#xA;Enable Enablement happens on multiple levels. Unblock sticking points. On any project there will be many sticking points including: (1) From above (e.g., leadership misalignments), (2) from within (e.g., intra-team process, dynamics, lack of cohesion etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flavors Of Exhaustion</title>
      <link>/posts/flavors-of-exhaustion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/flavors-of-exhaustion/</guid>
      <description>There are several flavors of exhaustion. Here’s the taxonomy.&#xA;Exhaustion by going shallow This is my enemy. This is what I’ve been doing the past few days as I onboard at a new company (oh, I’m now at Facebook!). But I’m doing a million little things, deep on none. It can be draining. But I know it’s finite. That hasn’t always been the case. I would debilitate myself, confusing activity for outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Less</title>
      <link>/posts/do-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/do-less/</guid>
      <description>We flew back from Boston a few days ago. I’ve encountered my share of turbulence on planes but this was the worst I had ever experienced. The metallic rattling of luggage in the overheads was sickening. I imagined getting torn to bits at 30k feet. I looked down at Lev, my boy, in the next seat. I noticed his thick wavy hair, freckled cheeks – pure boyishness! He was calmly staring at the seat ahead.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lua Turns 3 years old</title>
      <link>/posts/lua-turns-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/lua-turns-3/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Lua turned 3 years old. She helped me get through my dark days. She still does. And her ability to navigate people (already!) amazes me. She has such a giant personality. Definitely a proud daddy. I’ve had this habit for a long time where I write down my thought process for decisions and big events. I’ll periodically review them to either understand flaws/gaps in my thinking with the benefit of hindsight, or pat myself on the back for my prescience (not frequent, but it sometimes happens).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The space between sets</title>
      <link>/posts/the-space-between-sets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-space-between-sets/</guid>
      <description>If you asked me as a teenager I would have told you the payoff of workouts was in the primal aspects of the activity, the immediate feelings. It was about seeing how hard I could push the body. All that adolescent aggression had to get channelled somehow. This was easy and satisfying. It was about adrenaline, the ‘pump’.&#xA;Later it was about the effects of the workout, over a longer time period, seeing the progress of lifting x yesterday, x+1 today.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Factory Floor</title>
      <link>/posts/factory-floor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/factory-floor/</guid>
      <description>The cursor pulses hot green against the black terminal. A few quick taps execute the script. I watch the simulation unfold on the screen. Then, a stocatto barrage of keystrokes: Simulation number 39…no change from 38…The pX protein displays kinetics suggesting diffusion as the primary mechanic of nucleus traversal. In the presence of DNA breaks the molecular kinetics change and the molecule activates a cascade catalyzing repair complex formation…&#xA;I stop and lean back in the creaky lab chair.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 21:37:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I use this space to share updates on Product management practice, essays and general observations. Last year I battled a blood cancer cancer. You can read about that at that on Chemolog ebook&#xA;Here’s a short-list of useful links:&#xA;Proud member of the Leukemia and Lymphoma Society Big Climb Executive team&#xA;Inventor of COREwheels. See it on Instagram&#xA;Profile on LinkedIn&#xA;Github&#xA;Reading list Good Reads&#xA;Startup mentor and Advisor</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye Grandma</title>
      <link>/posts/goodbye-grandma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/goodbye-grandma/</guid>
      <description>On the way to seeing her I jotted down the memories, talking point bullets in my notebook: the warm feeling from sitting on the carpet as a kid, the smell of spaghetti and meatballs permeating the air on a random weeknight; coming over for breakfast across the driveway for Kasha; etc. I wanted to sit with her and share those memories, I knew by this point she wasn’t likely to be lucid but still, maybe she could hear/recognize my voice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemolog</title>
      <link>/chemolog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/chemolog/</guid>
      <description>In 2018 I was diagnosed with an aggressive blood cancer. I&amp;rsquo;ve compiled the blog I kept as an ebook (I&amp;rsquo;ve since taken down the blog itself).&#xA;Chemolog ebook</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chabot half marathon race report</title>
      <link>/posts/chabot-half-marathon-race-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/chabot-half-marathon-race-report/</guid>
      <description>If you emphasize the physical side of training you may become superbly conditioned but mentally not advanced at all. On the other hand, if you concentrate on the mental aspect, it is inevitable that the physical side will follow. My golden rule is to train for the mental toughness and not to train for the physical development.&#xA;Herb Elliott (world champion middle distance runner) This race comes at about day 30 in a new role.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Science</title>
      <link>/posts/leavingscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/leavingscience/</guid>
      <description>I went into science to remain a child. Where else can exploration for its own sake be considered a value? I did an MS in molecular biology and research in mathematics. I wanted to establish a foundation for understanding how things work. In a sense I wanted to learn how to learn. But I also worked on cool questions like:&#xA;How do epigenetic modifications influence evolution? why do anesthetics affect virtually all life forms like a magic light switch on consciousness?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Sevoflurance with a sister anesthetic</title>
      <link>/posts/comparisonofsevoflurane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/comparisonofsevoflurane/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a draft paper I wrote (and never got around to submitting) while working as a (molecular biologist) researcher at UCSF: Comparing Sevoflurane with a Sister Anesthetic, CHF2OCH(CF3)2 in Rats. The focus was exploring the possibility of brain metabolite formation in response to inhaled anesthetics. This topic matters since there is a link between exposure to these agents and cognitive impairment in children. Could we perhaps construct anesthetics without those negative effects?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNA folding forces; journal club presentation</title>
      <link>/posts/bioinformatics-investigating-the-forces-involved-in-dna-folding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/bioinformatics-investigating-the-forces-involved-in-dna-folding/</guid>
      <description>Notes from a journal club presentation I gave to the Mathematics, Chemistry and Molecular Biology faculty in 2007. This was an elegant study, called on the effect of Force on Mononucleosomal Dynamics. Basically the investigators used optical tweezers to perturb DNA to see about the coiling forces involved in wrapping and unwrapping DNA. This is important since DNA - which is often coiled or otherwise folded - must be accessed with very specific timing for things like genes to be transcribed to make functional proteins out of them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using siRNA to understand inhaled anesthetics</title>
      <link>/posts/using-sirna-to-understand-inhaled-anesthetic-action-experiment-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/using-sirna-to-understand-inhaled-anesthetic-action-experiment-design/</guid>
      <description>An Experimental Design I wrote as a researcher at UCSF proposing the use of small interfering RNA (siRNA) to elucidate the mechanisms by which inhaled anesthetics work. More specifically the idea is to infuse siRNA into the lumbar region of the spinal cord of rat to perturb the receptors thought to be responsible for inducing general anesthesia (e.g., Glycine, NMDA, etc.). siRNA experiment proposal&#xA;The main benefit of this approach is that it bypasses the need to engineer genetic mutant strains (say, of mice - which we also did).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review - N.Ferguson’s War of the world</title>
      <link>/posts/review-for-n.-fergusons-war-of-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/review-for-n.-fergusons-war-of-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Having just completed the excellent study of the past century in war, &amp;lsquo;The War of the World&amp;rsquo; by Niall Ferguson, I though I&amp;rsquo;d jot down a few notes as much for my own recollection (of the 600+ pager) as well as for those interested. Let me start with a few broad strokes to try and summarize some of the book&amp;rsquo;s findings:&#xA;Ferguson lists three ingredients as key predictive indicators of the descent of societies into genocide and brutal conflict of the type seen over and again throughout the past century (and more recently in Yugoslavia and Rwanda).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Annotating the Drosophila Genome</title>
      <link>/posts/bioinformatics-annotating-drosophila-genome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/bioinformatics-annotating-drosophila-genome/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a Bioinformatics Study annotating the Drosophila Erecta genome as part of a concerted effort to annotate the entire genome. What was really cool about this was tracing the branch points between species - you can literally see the differences at a genetic level (e.g., introns, or non-coding snippets of DNA).&#xA;The study was spearheaded by Washington U. in partnership with SFSU and I participated as part of a graduate class I took in 2007.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2009 Boston Marathon Race Report</title>
      <link>/posts/goboston-marathon-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/goboston-marathon-2009/</guid>
      <description>The day begins at 4:30. I must have eaten more than I can remember the previous night. I cooked up a vat of pasta, garlic bread and salad for a few folks including some fellow K-star runners. We watch chariots of fire on the 40” screen while shoveling the food down.&#xA;Out the door I get some green tea and honey at the local Starbucks (a staple for my marathons). On the bus ride over the course I feel disconcertingly unexcited.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/posts/masterynotego/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/masterynotego/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/posts/pure-simplicity-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/pure-simplicity-wins/</guid>
      <description>2022 ends with Covid It&amp;rsquo;s the final day of 2022</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
