<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mindset on Making Principles</title>
    <link>/tags/mindset/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mindset on Making Principles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Ari Akerstein 2006</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/mindset/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flavors Of Exhaustion</title>
      <link>/posts/flavors-of-exhaustion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/flavors-of-exhaustion/</guid>
      <description>There are several flavors of exhaustion. Here’s the taxonomy.&#xA;Exhaustion by going shallow This is my enemy. This is what I’ve been doing the past few days as I onboard at a new company (oh, I’m now at Facebook!). But I’m doing a million little things, deep on none. It can be draining. But I know it’s finite. That hasn’t always been the case. I would debilitate myself, confusing activity for outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Less</title>
      <link>/posts/do-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/do-less/</guid>
      <description>We flew back from Boston a few days ago. I’ve encountered my share of turbulence on planes but this was the worst I had ever experienced. The metallic rattling of luggage in the overheads was sickening. I imagined getting torn to bits at 30k feet. I looked down at Lev, my boy, in the next seat. I noticed his thick wavy hair, freckled cheeks – pure boyishness! He was calmly staring at the seat ahead.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The space between sets</title>
      <link>/posts/the-space-between-sets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-space-between-sets/</guid>
      <description>If you asked me as a teenager I would have told you the payoff of workouts was in the primal aspects of the activity, the immediate feelings. It was about seeing how hard I could push the body. All that adolescent aggression had to get channelled somehow. This was easy and satisfying. It was about adrenaline, the ‘pump’.&#xA;Later it was about the effects of the workout, over a longer time period, seeing the progress of lifting x yesterday, x+1 today.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
